# Yi Wei

## Department of Automation, Tsinghua University

Tel: (+86) 18513216395, Email: y-wei19@mails.tsinghua.edu.cn, Website: https://weivithu.github.io/

#### RESEARCH INTEREST

My research interests include computer vision, robotics and computer graphics. In particular, I am interested in 3D scene understanding and 3D reconstruction. I love the research topic which has practical application, such as AR/VR and autonomous driving. I would like to leverage 3D vision techniques to benefit our lives.

#### **EDUCATION**

## Tsinghua University, Department of Automation

PhD student in Automation, supervised by Prof. Jiwen Lu

iduent in Automation, supervised by Proj. Jiwen Lu

Tsinghua University, Department of Electronic Engineering
Bachelor student in Electronic Engineering, GPA: 3.66/4.0 (rank: 6/245)

Beijing No.5 High School Sep 2009 – Jul 2015

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### ByteDance - Beijing, China

2019

Sep 2019 - Present

Aug 2015 - Jun 2019

[Intern] Group "SLAM & 3D Vision", Advised by Hengkai Guo.

- · Research topic: self-supervised depth estimation, plane-assisted multi-view stereo, multiple plane detection.
- · Engineer topic: Shape AR, rectangle tracking.

### Microsoft Research Asia - Beijing, China

2018

[Research Intern] Intelligent Multimedia Group. Advised by Dr. Chunyu Wang.

· Research topic: multi-view hand pose estimation.

#### Tsinghua University - Beijing, China

2018

Intelligent Vision Group (IVG). Advised by Prof. Jiwen Lu.

- · Conditional single-view shape modeling for multi-view reconstruction (CVPR 2019).
- · Developed an improved evaluation framework to partially address the problem of FID.

# Sensetime – Beijing, China

2017

[Research Intern] Group "Video Intelligence" (camera department). Advised by Dr. Hongwei Qin.

- · Leveraged quantization and mimic to compress tiny model for object detection (ECCV 2018).
- · Developed an framework iterated between quantization and channel pruning for model compression (already been applied to market products).

## Tsinghua University - Beijing, China

2017

Visual Computing Lab. Advised by Prof. Guijin Wang.

· Designed the Two-Stream Binocular Network (TSBnet) to detect fingertips from binocular images and created a binocular dataset (VCIP 2017).

# DeePhi Tech (Xilinx)- Beijing, China

2016

[Engineer Intern] Advised by Hong Luo.

· Major developer of a real-time detector using Squeezenet and R-FCN (already been applied to company demo).

## **PUBLICATIONS**

- Yi Wei\*, Ziyi Wang\*, Yongming Rao \*, Jiwen Lu and Jie Zhou, "PV-RAFT: Point-Voxel Correlation Fields for Scene Flow Estimation of Point Clouds". CVPR 2021.
- Yi Wei, Shang Su, Jiwen Lu and Jie Zhou, "FGR: Frustum-Aware Geometric Reasoning for Weakly Supervised 3D Vehicle Detection". ICRA 2021.
- Yi Wei\*, Shaohui Liu\*, Wang Zhao\*, Jiwen Lu and Jie Zhou, "Conditional Single-view Shape Generation for Multi-view Stereo Reconstruction". CVPR 2019.
- Yi Wei, Xinyu Pan, Hongwei Qin and Junjie Yan, "Quantization mimic: Towards very tiny cnn for object detection". ECCV 2018.
- Yi Wei, Guijin Wang, Cairong Zhang, Hengkai Guo, Xinghao Chen, Huazhong Yang, "Two-stream binocular network: Accurate near field finger detection based on binocular images". VCIP 2017 Best Student Paper.

### **AWARDS**

- · 2018 Caixiong Scholarship (Tsinghua Research Excellence Scholarship)
- · 2018 Baogang Outstanding Scholarship
- · 2017 Qualcomm Scholarship
- · 2017 Sensetime Undergraduate Scholarship
- · 2017 National Scholarship, Tsinghua University
- · VCIP 2017 Best Student Paper Award

- 10 people in Tsinghua University
- 1 person in Tsinghua University
- 30 people in Tsinghua University
- -30 people in China

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

**Programming:** C/C++, Python, MATLAB, SQL, Verilog, LATEX, Linux/Unix

Language: Mandarin, English